<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>books | Andrea Merlina</title>
    <link>https://27am.github.io/tags/books/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://27am.github.io/tags/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>books</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://27am.github.io/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>books</title>
      <link>https://27am.github.io/tags/books/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading</title>
      <link>https://27am.github.io/pages/reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://27am.github.io/pages/reading/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I love to read, and I try to allocate to book as much time as I can. Books makes you travel without renouncing the comfort of your sofa and the warmth of a cup a tea. They are teachers and explorers. Throughout the years I have been reading a decent number of books, here I am trying to track down what has been my journey as a reader.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;currently-reading&#34;&gt;Currently reading&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Consciousness and the brain&lt;/strong&gt;, deciphering how the brain codes our thoughts &lt;em&gt;by Stanislas Dehaene&lt;/em&gt;. The author is a french neuroscientist This is an interesting read about ourselves. First of all there is a lot of imprecision surrounding the definition of counsciousness. What does it mean to be conscious of possess consciousness? Read more about the topic &lt;a href=&#34;https://27am.github.io/post/neuro/consciousness/&#34;&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2019&#34;&gt;2019&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Code&lt;/strong&gt;: The hidden language of computer hardware and software &lt;em&gt;by Charles Petzold&lt;/em&gt;. It is hard to describe how much I loved this book. The author is supremely gifted to guide the reader through a compelling and approachable journey to the inner mechanics of computers. The book is suitable for whatever background the reader might have. Extremely suggested for whomever is slightly curious about technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;21 lecciones para el siglo XXI&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;by Juval Noah Harari&lt;/em&gt;. The title is in spanish because I read the book in spanish. The narration is well developed but I found it less coherent than the previous two books of the author. Okay, it might be partly due to the fact that I was frequently checking out terms on the way, but every chapter is pretty much self contained and can be read autonomously. This can be interpreted both as an advantage or a disadvantage based on reading tastes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Black holes &amp;amp; time warps&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;by Kip Thorne&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
