<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pages | Andrea Merlina</title>
    <link>https://27am.github.io/pages/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://27am.github.io/pages/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Pages</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://27am.github.io/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Pages</title>
      <link>https://27am.github.io/pages/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boardgames</title>
      <link>https://27am.github.io/pages/boardgames/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://27am.github.io/pages/boardgames/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am pretty much into boardgames. It has been a curiosity of mine since younger age, but I never explored this passion beyong a few plays of Risk and Monopoli.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Everything else left</title>
      <link>https://27am.github.io/pages/other/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://27am.github.io/pages/other/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;hey&#34;&gt;Hey!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was hard to decide the website organization and what to put on the upper bar.
This page contains &amp;ldquo;everything left&amp;rdquo;.
I am currently mostly thinking about food, wine, trips and painting but maybe something else will show up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clik on a tag below to search for relevant posts, if they are available. Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology</title>
      <link>https://27am.github.io/pages/technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://27am.github.io/pages/technology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I will be mostly writing about blockchain and cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click on a tag below to search for relevant posts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life inspiration</title>
      <link>https://27am.github.io/pages/inspiration/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://27am.github.io/pages/inspiration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Life is not only about work. It is not even about having fun all the time: try eating day after day the same dish and sooner more than later you will end up hating it.
Motivation is what sits behind the curtrains and pulls the strings of our daily actions. However motivation is like a fragile plant that needs daily care. This page is a small collection of different resources, helpful tids and bits to refresh motivation and perhaps provide a different perspective on daily life. Sometimes we cannot change what happens, and yet we always have control on how we see it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;inspiration&#34;&gt;Inspiration&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UF8uR6Z6KLc&#34;&gt;Steve Jobs&amp;rsquo; speech at Stanford&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EWPFmdAWRZ0&amp;amp;t=249s&#34;&gt;Pale blue dot speech by Carl Sagan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;reflection&#34;&gt;Reflection&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qX6NztnPU-4&#34;&gt;An old philosopher faces his own death&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;quotes&#34;&gt;Quotes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Collections of quotes that I like and find inspiring :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Everything we hear is an opinion, not a fact. Everything we see is a perspective, not the truth.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;
― Marcus Aurelius&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“The real act of discovery consists not in finding new lands, but in seeing with new eyes.”&lt;/em&gt;
― Marcel Proust&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;He suffers more than necessary, who suffers before it is necessary.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;
― Seneca&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;If a man knows not to which port he sails, no wind is favorable.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;
― Seneca&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Luck is what happens when preparation meets opportunity.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;
― Seneca&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Honesty is a very expensive gift. Don’t expect it from cheap people.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;
― Warren Buffett&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;When they say you can&amp;rsquo;t, they show you their limits, not yours.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;
– Kevin Keenoo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;A lot of people have gone further than they thought they could because someone else thought they could.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;
– Zig Ziglar&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;The mind, once stretched by a new idea, never returns to its original dimensions.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;
― Ralph Waldo Emerson&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;There is only one thing that makes a dream impossible to achieve: the fear of failure.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;
– Paulo Coelho&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;There are many things of which a wise man might wish to be ignorant&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;
– Ralph Waldo Emerson&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“The man who asks a question is a fool for a minute, the man who does not ask is a fool for life.”&lt;/em&gt;
– Confucius&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“A ship in harbour is safe, but that is not what ships are built for.”&lt;/em&gt;
– William G.T. Shedd&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“I cannot remember the books I&amp;rsquo;ve read any more than the meals I have eaten; even so, they have made me.”&lt;/em&gt;
― Ralph Waldo Emerson&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“I am always doing that which I cannot do, in order that I may learn how to do it.”&lt;/em&gt;
– Pablo Picasso&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“You don&amp;rsquo;t have to see the whole staircase. Just take the first step.”&lt;/em&gt;
― Martin Luther King&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Most geniuses—especially those who lead others—prosper not by deconstructing intricate complexities but by exploiting unrecognized simplicities.”&lt;/em&gt;
— Andy Benoit&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“The greatest shortcoming of the human race is our inability to understand the exponential function.”&lt;/em&gt;
— Albert Allen Bartlett&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;What is common to many is taken least care of, for all men have greater regard for what is their own than for what they possess in common with others.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;
— Aristotle&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Everything should be made as simple as possible, but not simpler.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;
— Albert Einstein&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Simple things should be simple, complex things should be possible.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;
– Alan Kay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading</title>
      <link>https://27am.github.io/pages/reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://27am.github.io/pages/reading/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I love to read, and I try to allocate to book as much time as I can. Books makes you travel without renouncing the comfort of your sofa and the warmth of a cup a tea. They are teachers and explorers. Throughout the years I have been reading a decent number of books, here I am trying to track down what has been my journey as a reader.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;currently-reading&#34;&gt;Currently reading&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Consciousness and the brain&lt;/strong&gt;, deciphering how the brain codes our thoughts &lt;em&gt;by Stanislas Dehaene&lt;/em&gt;. The author is a french neuroscientist This is an interesting read about ourselves. First of all there is a lot of imprecision surrounding the definition of counsciousness. What does it mean to be conscious of possess consciousness? Read more about the topic &lt;a href=&#34;https://27am.github.io/post/neuro/consciousness/&#34;&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2019&#34;&gt;2019&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Code&lt;/strong&gt;: The hidden language of computer hardware and software &lt;em&gt;by Charles Petzold&lt;/em&gt;. It is hard to describe how much I loved this book. The author is supremely gifted to guide the reader through a compelling and approachable journey to the inner mechanics of computers. The book is suitable for whatever background the reader might have. Extremely suggested for whomever is slightly curious about technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;21 lecciones para el siglo XXI&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;by Juval Noah Harari&lt;/em&gt;. The title is in spanish because I read the book in spanish. The narration is well developed but I found it less coherent than the previous two books of the author. Okay, it might be partly due to the fact that I was frequently checking out terms on the way, but every chapter is pretty much self contained and can be read autonomously. This can be interpreted both as an advantage or a disadvantage based on reading tastes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Black holes &amp;amp; time warps&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;by Kip Thorne&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
